<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>paddlesports on HowIsJT</title>
    <link>https://howisjt.com/tags/paddlesports/</link>
    <description>Recent content in paddlesports on HowIsJT</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 19:00:52 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://howisjt.com/tags/paddlesports/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kayak Build</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-paddling-kayak-build/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-paddling-kayak-build/</guid>
      <description>Finished! Well it took far longer than I anticipated &amp;ndash; nearly two years of weekends and holidays &amp;ndash; but I&amp;rsquo;ve completed this project. I&amp;rsquo;ve documented the process in a stand-alone blog linked below. It was written diary style rather than &amp;ldquo;instructables&amp;rdquo; style, but contains numerous images, galleries, lessons learned and even a few videos. It would be helpful to anyone considering taking on a stitch-and-glue boat project such as this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayou Manchac</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-paddling-manchac/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-paddling-manchac/</guid>
      <description>My residence in southeast East Baton Rouge parish is less than 1-1/5 miles from the Amite River and 4-1/2 miles as the crow flies from Bayou Manchac. Having an enjoyment of paddling I&amp;rsquo;ve been on several excursions on the lower Manchac out to the Amite and back. I discovered a boat ramp into Bayou Manchac at the end of Ducros Rd, off Hwy. 42 in Prairieville. I&amp;rsquo;ve not paddled down the Amite itself - too chicken - as I&amp;rsquo;ve read of the hazards of current, fallen trees and snags.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Florida&#39;s Santa Fe River</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-florida-santafe-river/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 01:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-florida-santafe-river/</guid>
      <description>Officially, Florida&amp;rsquo;s Santa Fe originates from Santa Fe Lake, northeast of Gainesville, and flows 75 miles westward until it meets the Suwanee. For three miles, the river actually dives underground forming the famous natural bridge over which Florida&amp;rsquo;s old Bellamy Road crossed. The &amp;ldquo;sink&amp;rdquo; is in scenic O&amp;rsquo;Leno (Old Leno) State Park and the &amp;ldquo;rise&amp;rdquo; three miles downstream is in River Rise State Park off US 41/441. This behavior is not uncommon of streams in karst limestone regions and it neatly divides the Santa Fe into up-river and down-river.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paddling</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-paddling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-paddling/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed being on the water since childhood and have fond memories of family reunions at my cousin&amp;rsquo;s lake houses where we&amp;rsquo;d swim, boat, water ski, and play.
Kayaking Residing just a couple miles from the beach in Sarasota, Florida caused me to break a commandment. Yes, I coveted my neighbor&amp;rsquo;s kayak. Not my actual neighbor, as he didn&amp;rsquo;t have one, but essentially any kayak I saw riding the roof rack of so, so many cars down local roads.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
