<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Florida on HowIsJT</title>
    <link>https://howisjt.com/tags/florida/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Florida on HowIsJT</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 19:00:52 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://howisjt.com/tags/florida/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Miami Beach</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-florida-miami-beach/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-florida-miami-beach/</guid>
      <description>TRIP PHOTO ALBUM I&amp;rsquo;ve been fortunate to visit Miami and Miami Beach three or four times back in the late &amp;rsquo;90s and mid 2000s. As the port of embarkation for a Bahamas cruise my wife and I will be visiting Miami Beach again in the near future. This page is essentially my &amp;ldquo;Cliff&amp;rsquo;s Notes&amp;rdquo; for my visit so I&amp;rsquo;ll have a single aggregated source of information.
A Miami Beach Chronology Below is a chronology of the development and growth of Miami Beach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Florida&#39;s Santa Fe River</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-florida-santafe-river/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 01:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-florida-santafe-river/</guid>
      <description>Officially, Florida&amp;rsquo;s Santa Fe originates from Santa Fe Lake, northeast of Gainesville, and flows 75 miles westward until it meets the Suwanee. For three miles, the river actually dives underground forming the famous natural bridge over which Florida&amp;rsquo;s old Bellamy Road crossed. The &amp;ldquo;sink&amp;rdquo; is in scenic O&amp;rsquo;Leno (Old Leno) State Park and the &amp;ldquo;rise&amp;rdquo; three miles downstream is in River Rise State Park off US 41/441. This behavior is not uncommon of streams in karst limestone regions and it neatly divides the Santa Fe into up-river and down-river.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camping in Florida</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-florida-camping/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-florida-camping/</guid>
      <description>Camping in several of Florida&amp;rsquo;s State Parks has been very enjoyable trips creating fond memories. In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll list them by region within the state.
Big Lagoon State Park, Pensacola - camp siteSouth Florida The Florida Keys I&amp;rsquo;ve been camping in the Florida Keys twice. Both were very short, one night visits. The first was in a private campground down close to Key West. I don&amp;rsquo;t recall the name or specific location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Southwest Florida</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-florida-sarasota/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-florida-sarasota/</guid>
      <description>Beautiful Sarasota was our home during the 2000&amp;rsquo;s, arriving for a new job just months after getting married in 1999. This Gulf coast town and its brilliant white sand beaches is where we started our family with a puppy, and then two sons. This post describes many of my favorite places and activities in southwest Florida - the places I miss the most.
Homes But I&amp;rsquo;ll start with where we lived.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Florida Home Landscape</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/landscape-florida-res-glenridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/landscape-florida-res-glenridge/</guid>
      <description>My wife and I were homeowners in the Southgate Ridge neighborhood of Sarasota, Florida. It was a typical retiree bungalow repurposed as a starter home located south of downtown and less than five miles from the beach; add another mile if you simply had to continue north to the Siesta Key Beach pavilion. The home was simple, had only one bathroom, but it was paradise. About a year into our ownership, long enough to recover from all of those extra closing costs, we were ready to re-landscape the front yard.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
