<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HowIsJT</title>
    <link>https://howisjt.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on HowIsJT</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://howisjt.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chicago</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-chicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-chicago/</guid>
      <description>My wife, sons and I spent four fantastic days exploring downtown Chicago visiting museums, galleries, parks and restaurants. We anticipated a typical summer trip, but our arrival coincided with a late season cold front which brought several days of unseasonably cool weather following that initial day of rain.
Trip Planning CitiPass claims they save you 48%. I didn&amp;rsquo;t do the math, but that seems about right. Citipass saved us hundreds of dollars and provided perks at most of the museums including 3D movies, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kayak Build</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-paddling-kayak-build/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-paddling-kayak-build/</guid>
      <description>Finished! Well it took far longer than I anticipated &amp;ndash; nearly two years of weekends and holidays &amp;ndash; but I&amp;rsquo;ve completed this project. I&amp;rsquo;ve documented the process in a stand-alone blog linked below. It was written diary style rather than &amp;ldquo;instructables&amp;rdquo; style, but contains numerous images, galleries, lessons learned and even a few videos. It would be helpful to anyone considering taking on a stitch-and-glue boat project such as this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Theme Site</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/tech-two-hugo-themes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 01:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/tech-two-hugo-themes/</guid>
      <description>Website themes are great, providing a consistent appearance and layout of all pages in your website. Occasionally the need arises to format a particular section of your webite uniquely. Here I will describe how I&amp;rsquo;ve achieved this using two different themes in this website. I learned about this technique on this Discourse thread As I began implementing this I ran into a few challenges that took me a bit of time to figure out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Texas Campgrounds</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-texas-camping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-texas-camping/</guid>
      <description>Texas offers loads of interesting places, landscapes and outdoor activities - yet I&amp;rsquo;ve visited the state only a few times, with just one visit to a few parks in the Austin area. A few photos from this trip are below. This blog is to explore potential tent-friendly campsites and attractions or points of interest that we&amp;rsquo;d like to visit and experience as a family.
Potential Campgrounds As usual I began my search by looking at maps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IP Security Cameras</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/tech-home-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/tech-home-security/</guid>
      <description>Reports of car and home burglaries in and around my neighborhood reported on the NextDoor app persuaded me to investigate a low-cost home security camera system. Many neighbors already have them so I figured &amp;ldquo;why not.&amp;rdquo; Much inspiration for the system I built came from TechnoDadLife and from Peyanski on Tech. Because I already had an older Dell Core 2 Duo desktop set up as a home NAS using OpenMediaVault, I decided to simply install a CCTV monitoring application onto that LINUX box since a) it is already running 24/7 and b) its use as a NAS is infrequent - meaning family members rarely access it so the computer has plenty of resources to spare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/privacy/</guid>
      <description>This site implements cookies to track visitation via Google analytics (so I can learn how many people visit and which pages are most popular.)
Also, the Disqus commenting opportunity at the footer of each blog post implements cookies in order to enable commenting.
Lastly, the social media share buttons enable cookies to facilitate the sharing of my post thru your social media account - if you choose to do so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayou Manchac</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-paddling-manchac/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-paddling-manchac/</guid>
      <description>My residence in southeast East Baton Rouge parish is less than 1-1/5 miles from the Amite River and 4-1/2 miles as the crow flies from Bayou Manchac. Having an enjoyment of paddling I&amp;rsquo;ve been on several excursions on the lower Manchac out to the Amite and back. I discovered a boat ramp into Bayou Manchac at the end of Ducros Rd, off Hwy. 42 in Prairieville. I&amp;rsquo;ve not paddled down the Amite itself - too chicken - as I&amp;rsquo;ve read of the hazards of current, fallen trees and snags.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dadeville Lakehouse Landscape</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/landscape-alabama-lakefront/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/landscape-alabama-lakefront/</guid>
      <description>At the end of my dad&amp;rsquo;s construction career he designed and built his grand finale - a home for his bride in her hometown. I was still in school at LSU but found time to draft plans for my parent&amp;rsquo;s lake house. The home was constructed into the hillside and of course excavation, grading, and utilities left scars. The intent of my landscape plan was to heal these scars and to reunite the home with the surrounding woodland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yancey County, NC</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-burnsville/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-burnsville/</guid>
      <description>View my Google photo album of this trip. Also in the works is a video of our adventures and sight seeing.
I spent part of my youth growing up on a beautiful farm outside of Burnsville, NC. We were a hard working family on a beautiful 120+ acre property fronting the Cane River where we raised beef cattle and grew tobacco and feed corn, eventually transitioning to blueberries, raspberries and blackberries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shreveport Points of Interest</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-louisiana-shreveport/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-louisiana-shreveport/</guid>
      <description>Shreveport is my wife&amp;rsquo;s hometown so we get there fairly regularly. Here are a few places I like to visit.
Eats While there&amp;rsquo;s more to do in Shreveport than eat, let&amp;rsquo;s just say that there is no reason to go hungry while you&amp;rsquo;re there&amp;hellip;
Herby K&amp;rsquo;s Home of the shrimp buster sandwich.
They take about three jumbo shrimp and butterfly them, lightly deep fry them, and drop them on a poboy bun with lettuce and tomato.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nassau Bahamas</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-bahamas-nassau/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-bahamas-nassau/</guid>
      <description>TRIP PHOTO ALBUM I&amp;rsquo;ve been researching Nassau to determine what I&amp;rsquo;d like to see and do during our brief visit by cruise ship. Aside from Miami&amp;rsquo;s South Beach, Nassau presents the only opportunity to see and learn about Caribbean history on this trip. Below are my notes and lists from reading various texts (mostly Fodors) and web articles. I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ve overdone it, listing far more than anyone could see within the estimated eight hours of time we&amp;rsquo;ll have for shore leave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miami Beach</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-florida-miami-beach/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-florida-miami-beach/</guid>
      <description>TRIP PHOTO ALBUM I&amp;rsquo;ve been fortunate to visit Miami and Miami Beach three or four times back in the late &amp;rsquo;90s and mid 2000s. As the port of embarkation for a Bahamas cruise my wife and I will be visiting Miami Beach again in the near future. This page is essentially my &amp;ldquo;Cliff&amp;rsquo;s Notes&amp;rdquo; for my visit so I&amp;rsquo;ll have a single aggregated source of information.
A Miami Beach Chronology Below is a chronology of the development and growth of Miami Beach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avery Island</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-avery-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-avery-island/</guid>
      <description>During a day-trip to Avery Island we learned there&amp;rsquo;s much more to this south Louisiana curiosity than just hot sauce. There are two paid attractions on Avery Island: 1) Tours of the Tabasco factory (self-guided ~$5.50 each, more for guided group tours) and 2) Driving tour of the Jungle Gardens (additional $7 per person). Fees are for adults. There are slight discounts for seniors and young children.
Jeep photo opp for our kids We enjoyed our visit on the Friday following July 4, 2019, but we didn&amp;rsquo;t realize the plant would be closed for the holiday weekend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shortcodes Test</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/tech-shortcodes-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/tech-shortcodes-test/</guid>
      <description>Hugo Shortcodes Shortcodes are little snippets of code that can be called from within a post to perform an action. Hugo comes with a few shortcodes baked in such as &amp;ldquo;figure&amp;rdquo;, but others I&amp;rsquo;ve gleaned from internet searches and perhaps from my own tinkering.
Folder-based Image Gallery from a folder of pictures within &amp;ldquo;website/hugo/howisjt/static/&amp;rdquo;. Don&amp;rsquo;t put a slash in front of the &amp;ldquo;images&amp;rdquo; directory. This is different from all others. Youtube Just insert &amp;ldquo;youtube&amp;rdquo; with the unique video code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professional Recognition</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/planning-recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 01:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/planning-recognition/</guid>
      <description>Look, I&amp;rsquo;m not going to suggest that awards are just piling up on my desk, but I am fortunate to have worked on projects which have received awards, and also recognized for my volunteer efforts with my professional organization, the American Planning Association - Louisiana Chapter. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d use this post to keep track of them. I even got a photo with then-APA President Paul Farmer, FAICP at one of our state conferences held in Monroe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fort Leavenworth</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-kansas-leavenworth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-kansas-leavenworth/</guid>
      <description>The name Fort Leavenworth has always had ominous connotations to me. At the occasion of my oldest brother&amp;rsquo;s military retirement ceremony, I was presented a chance to go see for myself. The place is beautiful, perhaps not inside the prison itself, but Fort Leavenworth as a whole is quite attractive. The Santa Fe and Oregon trails crossed the Missouri River here at Ft. Leavenworth, and you can still see the depressions from the wagon trains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Image Gallery</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/tech-hugo-image-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/tech-hugo-image-gallery/</guid>
      <description>My new Hugo blog website wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be complete without the ability to host and display photos in an efficient, quick loading and mobile friendly manner. I searched around a bit examining several options. Each has pros and cons in my opinion, yet none of the sources for this code seemed to acknowledge the existence of the others. I&amp;rsquo;m providing links to the source where I found each of these, although those developers may have pulled it from somewhere else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Florida&#39;s Santa Fe River</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-florida-santafe-river/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 01:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-florida-santafe-river/</guid>
      <description>Officially, Florida&amp;rsquo;s Santa Fe originates from Santa Fe Lake, northeast of Gainesville, and flows 75 miles westward until it meets the Suwanee. For three miles, the river actually dives underground forming the famous natural bridge over which Florida&amp;rsquo;s old Bellamy Road crossed. The &amp;ldquo;sink&amp;rdquo; is in scenic O&amp;rsquo;Leno (Old Leno) State Park and the &amp;ldquo;rise&amp;rdquo; three miles downstream is in River Rise State Park off US 41/441. This behavior is not uncommon of streams in karst limestone regions and it neatly divides the Santa Fe into up-river and down-river.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Martin Alabama</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-alabama-lk-martin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-alabama-lk-martin/</guid>
      <description>Mom is a small town girl from Dadeville, Alabama. Small towns often have big families, and her Pearson family is no exception. There were three girls and three boys in her family, so I had five sets of aunts and uncles - all of whom resided in Alabama or returned to the state for their retirement. Pearson family reunions are held every summer at an uncle&amp;rsquo;s lake house, and we try to make it each year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camping in Florida</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-florida-camping/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-florida-camping/</guid>
      <description>Camping in several of Florida&amp;rsquo;s State Parks has been very enjoyable trips creating fond memories. In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll list them by region within the state.
Big Lagoon State Park, Pensacola - camp siteSouth Florida The Florida Keys I&amp;rsquo;ve been camping in the Florida Keys twice. Both were very short, one night visits. The first was in a private campground down close to Key West. I don&amp;rsquo;t recall the name or specific location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Southwest Florida</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-florida-sarasota/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-florida-sarasota/</guid>
      <description>Beautiful Sarasota was our home during the 2000&amp;rsquo;s, arriving for a new job just months after getting married in 1999. This Gulf coast town and its brilliant white sand beaches is where we started our family with a puppy, and then two sons. This post describes many of my favorite places and activities in southwest Florida - the places I miss the most.
Homes But I&amp;rsquo;ll start with where we lived.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Florida Home Landscape</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/landscape-florida-res-glenridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/landscape-florida-res-glenridge/</guid>
      <description>My wife and I were homeowners in the Southgate Ridge neighborhood of Sarasota, Florida. It was a typical retiree bungalow repurposed as a starter home located south of downtown and less than five miles from the beach; add another mile if you simply had to continue north to the Siesta Key Beach pavilion. The home was simple, had only one bathroom, but it was paradise. About a year into our ownership, long enough to recover from all of those extra closing costs, we were ready to re-landscape the front yard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baton Rouge Sights</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-louisiana-baton-rouge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-louisiana-baton-rouge/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve had friends and family come to visit over the years and we&amp;rsquo;re always looking for things to do and places to show them. So, I built a list! Most of these attractions involve history and culture that are unique to Baton Rouge. Below you&amp;rsquo;ll find a collection of my remarks, photos, and a map or two. Back Story As Edwin Edwards remarked about his governorships, I consider myself to be an &amp;ldquo;occasional&amp;rdquo; resident of Baton Rouge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birding in the South</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-birding/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-birding/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been interested in and fascinated by birds since childhood. During my high school and college years I forgot about it, not picking it back up again until I began my professional career.
Rekindled Interest My coworker Scott Knaus corrected my mis-identification of a chickadee, which I had foolishly called a &amp;ldquo;Black Capped&amp;rdquo; and he informed me it was more likely a &amp;ldquo;Carolina&amp;rdquo;. Oh, right. Many would have left it right there, but as my education included plant science and I appreciated the concept of &amp;ldquo;species,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;variety&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;cultivar,&amp;rdquo; I understood Scott&amp;rsquo;s point immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camping Chuck Box</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-camping-chuckbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-camping-chuckbox/</guid>
      <description>The kitchen and food prep is always a challenge when tent camping with the family. As a kid my dad took us camping in western North Carolina and I (vaguely) recall a rather elaborate setup with two large tents facing each other, and a heavy canvas tarp stretched in between, covering and protecting our dining and cooking area. There were boxes of food and supplies, large ice coolers, a Coleman stove and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camping in Louisiana</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-louisiana-camping/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-louisiana-camping/</guid>
      <description>My sons and I have enjoyed several tent camping trips in Louisiana and southern Mississippi. Sometimes, their friends have gone with us, and one trip was a church youth trip (which you&amp;rsquo;ll agree, aren&amp;rsquo;t typical camping trips.)
North Louisiana Caney Lake Campground - above Minden was a fun trip with our cousins. We all shared a campsite and everyone managed to find a space to spread out their sleeping bag in one of two tents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camping in South Mississippi</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-mississippi-camping/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-mississippi-camping/</guid>
      <description>Mississippi offers several beautiful campgrounds within an easy drive of Baton Rouge.
South Mississippi All of my tent camping experience in Mississippi has been in the southern part of the state. It&amp;rsquo;s a reasonably short drive from my home in Baton Rouge.
Clear Springs in Homochitto Forest Clear Springs campground is a hidden gem. Forest camping is terrific here surrounding this beautiful reservoir and facilities constructed during the Works Progress Administration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classic Celestron C8</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-astronomy-celestron/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 01:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-astronomy-celestron/</guid>
      <description>Back Story As a kid during the 1970&amp;rsquo;s I had two older brothers, both science whizzes, who got into amateur astronomy during their high school years. Guided by a fairly remarkable high school science teacher, one brother nearly won the state science fair through his experimentation with chilled film in a fabricated camera body conducting astrophotography. I was too young to really understand what he was doing, but my father bought the latest, greatest Schmidt-Cassgrain telescope for his sons to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiences with Google Compute Engine</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/tech-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/tech-cloud/</guid>
      <description>I was excited about the possibility of deploying &amp;ldquo;micro&amp;rdquo; webservers hosting sites which cost nothing - due to their tiny resource requirements and ability to fit within Google&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;always free&amp;rdquo; thresholds. This experimentation, and failures, led me to static site generators.
WordPress Won&amp;rsquo;t Run Free Initially, I was trying to deploy full-blown SQL-driven CMS sites using WordPress and Drupal. While some of my sites functioned for a while, eventually they all failed as I added content because the load just became overwhelming for GCE&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Micro&amp;rdquo; instance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Orleans Sights</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-louisiana-new-orleans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-louisiana-new-orleans/</guid>
      <description>As Baton Rouge is just an hour&amp;rsquo;s drive from the Big Easy, we get down for visits with friends and sightseeing several times each year.
History Below I offer my big, bad overview of the history of New Orleans; based on a variety of sources from the web or print books I&amp;rsquo;ve read over the years. I&amp;rsquo;ve failed to properly document them, so if this were a middle school English paper I&amp;rsquo;d get an &amp;ldquo;F&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paddling</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-paddling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-paddling/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed being on the water since childhood and have fond memories of family reunions at my cousin&amp;rsquo;s lake houses where we&amp;rsquo;d swim, boat, water ski, and play.
Kayaking Residing just a couple miles from the beach in Sarasota, Florida caused me to break a commandment. Yes, I coveted my neighbor&amp;rsquo;s kayak. Not my actual neighbor, as he didn&amp;rsquo;t have one, but essentially any kayak I saw riding the roof rack of so, so many cars down local roads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presenting without PowerPoint</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/planning-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/planning-presentation/</guid>
      <description>Death by PowerPoint is a comic metaphor for the all too common use of Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s product to produce and deliver the most dull, uninspired, and sleep inspiring lectures imaginable. Certainly, the software itself isn&amp;rsquo;t the culprit - it&amp;rsquo;s the uninspired user. But in an effort to &amp;ldquo;think out of the box&amp;rdquo; I decided to prepare and deliver a couple of lectures using on-screen presentation frameworks other than PowerPoint.
Presi Yes, Presi is a commercial product too, and it is now associated with disorienting, spinning on-screen shows that can give the audience indigestion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeking Dark Skies</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-astronomy-dark-sky/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-astronomy-dark-sky/</guid>
      <description>Until my interest in astronomy was resurrected in 2015 I never really gave city lights a second thought except when they shined through my bedroom window at night or when I considered the plight of sea turtles. As a Florida resident the problem with municipal and private property lighting along beaches was well known through the efforts of activists and subsequent legislation that seems to be making a positive difference for turtle hatchlings along at least some beaches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Development Projects</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/tech-web-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/tech-web-development/</guid>
      <description>My earliest website development began with static sites hosted at GeoCities and other no-cost hosting providers. Each never amounted to more than a dozen or so pages each, but I learned the basics of HTML and CSS. Future employment led me to WordPress and then to Drupal frameworks. Each presented benefits, challenges, and learning opportunities.
Twitter Bootstrap Site content development with WordPress - specifically custom coding certain pages to achieve desired effects - led me back to hard-coding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community Guidelines</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/guidelines/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve implemented Disqus commenting my this blog because I hope to learn from you, dear reader. From experience, I know that the responses in these commenting sections is often more informative than the author&amp;rsquo;s original post. This seems particularly true of technical blogs, perhaps less so of travel or hobby blog posts which are, of right, the opinion of their author.
So I look forward to reading your comments with the understanding that I won&amp;rsquo;t tolerate rudeness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>America&#39;s Great Solar Eclipse of 2017</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-astronomy-eclipse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-astronomy-eclipse/</guid>
      <description>By stroke of good fortune, one of my brothers lives outside of Anderson, South Carolina. His home was nearly in the center of the solar eclipse path, so I traveled from Louisiana with our family telescope to observe the eclipse with he, his wife, sons and friends. We enjoyed nearly perfectly clear skies for most of the event, though others - even family residing just a dozen miles away - suffered overcast skies totally obscuring totality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repowering a Snapper Comet</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-snapper-repower/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-snapper-repower/</guid>
      <description>I inherited a 27&amp;quot; Snapper Comet riding mower from a neighbor after it&amp;rsquo;s engine blew. Turns out, the owner had failed to change and ensure adequate engine oil, so it seised. I happily accepted the donation, initially attempted to rebuild the Honda engine, but eventually replaced it with a new engine. It ran well for a few years. Here&amp;rsquo;s the story.
A Gift Snapper A neighbor living a block away was the original owner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Washington DC Trip</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-dc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-dc/</guid>
      <description>My family was fortunate to be able to visit our nation&amp;rsquo;s capital right at the peak of the cherry blossoms during spring break of 2016. My oldest brother Fred and his wife Bonnie generously opened their home to us, inviting us to stay and also going with us on several days to visit the National Mall, enjoy some great dining, and ride the MetroRail around D.C. They live south of the city near one of the rail stops which makes commuting in very convenient.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/404/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/404/</guid>
      <description>Error 404: Page Not Found It seems that the page that you&amp;rsquo;re trying to access doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist. :worried: If you&amp;rsquo;re sure that it exists, chances are it might have been moved to a new link! You may search for it on the home page. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/about/</guid>
      <description>So, how is J.T.? Well, I&amp;rsquo;m doing great! Thanks for asking.
Early in my career I was presented a &amp;ldquo;Jack of All Trades&amp;rdquo; award which I though was pretty cool. It was just some silly clip art inkjet printed onto cardstock, but I knew it was significant because of who presented it to me. Twenty-five years have passed since since then, and I&amp;rsquo;ve continued to fill many roles for my employers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
