<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>travel on HowIsJT</title>
    <link>https://howisjt.com/categories/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in travel on HowIsJT</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 19:00:52 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://howisjt.com/categories/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Easter in Galveston</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-galveston/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-galveston/</guid>
      <description>Our family spring trip this year will be to Galveston, Texas for Easter weekend. Galveston Island is roughly a 5-hour drive from home, so we will be able to get three nights, two full days, and two half-days of fun out of this family trip. This will be our first pleasure trip into Texas as a family. We rented an Air B&amp;amp;B cottage next to Galveston&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Silk Stocking&amp;rdquo; district. The rental is pet-friendly and has a fenced backyard so our dog Woody can travel with us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-chicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-chicago/</guid>
      <description>My wife, sons and I spent four fantastic days exploring downtown Chicago visiting museums, galleries, parks and restaurants. We anticipated a typical summer trip, but our arrival coincided with a late season cold front which brought several days of unseasonably cool weather following that initial day of rain.
Trip Planning CitiPass claims they save you 48%. I didn&amp;rsquo;t do the math, but that seems about right. Citipass saved us hundreds of dollars and provided perks at most of the museums including 3D movies, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Texas Campgrounds</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-texas-camping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-texas-camping/</guid>
      <description>Texas offers loads of interesting places, landscapes and outdoor activities - yet I&amp;rsquo;ve visited the state only a few times, with just one visit to a few parks in the Austin area. A few photos from this trip are below. This blog is to explore potential tent-friendly campsites and attractions or points of interest that we&amp;rsquo;d like to visit and experience as a family.
Potential Campgrounds As usual I began my search by looking at maps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayou Manchac</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-paddling-manchac/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-paddling-manchac/</guid>
      <description>My residence in southeast East Baton Rouge parish is less than 1-1/5 miles from the Amite River and 4-1/2 miles as the crow flies from Bayou Manchac. Having an enjoyment of paddling I&amp;rsquo;ve been on several excursions on the lower Manchac out to the Amite and back. I discovered a boat ramp into Bayou Manchac at the end of Ducros Rd, off Hwy. 42 in Prairieville. I&amp;rsquo;ve not paddled down the Amite itself - too chicken - as I&amp;rsquo;ve read of the hazards of current, fallen trees and snags.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yancey County, NC</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-burnsville/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-burnsville/</guid>
      <description>View my Google photo album of this trip. Also in the works is a video of our adventures and sight seeing.
I spent part of my youth growing up on a beautiful farm outside of Burnsville, NC. We were a hard working family on a beautiful 120+ acre property fronting the Cane River where we raised beef cattle and grew tobacco and feed corn, eventually transitioning to blueberries, raspberries and blackberries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shreveport Points of Interest</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-louisiana-shreveport/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-louisiana-shreveport/</guid>
      <description>Shreveport is my wife&amp;rsquo;s hometown so we get there fairly regularly. Here are a few places I like to visit.
Eats While there&amp;rsquo;s more to do in Shreveport than eat, let&amp;rsquo;s just say that there is no reason to go hungry while you&amp;rsquo;re there&amp;hellip;
Herby K&amp;rsquo;s Home of the shrimp buster sandwich.
They take about three jumbo shrimp and butterfly them, lightly deep fry them, and drop them on a poboy bun with lettuce and tomato.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nassau Bahamas</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-bahamas-nassau/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-bahamas-nassau/</guid>
      <description>TRIP PHOTO ALBUM I&amp;rsquo;ve been researching Nassau to determine what I&amp;rsquo;d like to see and do during our brief visit by cruise ship. Aside from Miami&amp;rsquo;s South Beach, Nassau presents the only opportunity to see and learn about Caribbean history on this trip. Below are my notes and lists from reading various texts (mostly Fodors) and web articles. I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ve overdone it, listing far more than anyone could see within the estimated eight hours of time we&amp;rsquo;ll have for shore leave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miami Beach</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-florida-miami-beach/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-florida-miami-beach/</guid>
      <description>TRIP PHOTO ALBUM I&amp;rsquo;ve been fortunate to visit Miami and Miami Beach three or four times back in the late &amp;rsquo;90s and mid 2000s. As the port of embarkation for a Bahamas cruise my wife and I will be visiting Miami Beach again in the near future. This page is essentially my &amp;ldquo;Cliff&amp;rsquo;s Notes&amp;rdquo; for my visit so I&amp;rsquo;ll have a single aggregated source of information.
A Miami Beach Chronology Below is a chronology of the development and growth of Miami Beach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avery Island</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-avery-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-avery-island/</guid>
      <description>During a day-trip to Avery Island we learned there&amp;rsquo;s much more to this south Louisiana curiosity than just hot sauce. There are two paid attractions on Avery Island: 1) Tours of the Tabasco factory (self-guided ~$5.50 each, more for guided group tours) and 2) Driving tour of the Jungle Gardens (additional $7 per person). Fees are for adults. There are slight discounts for seniors and young children.
Jeep photo opp for our kids We enjoyed our visit on the Friday following July 4, 2019, but we didn&amp;rsquo;t realize the plant would be closed for the holiday weekend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fort Leavenworth</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-kansas-leavenworth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-kansas-leavenworth/</guid>
      <description>The name Fort Leavenworth has always had ominous connotations to me. At the occasion of my oldest brother&amp;rsquo;s military retirement ceremony, I was presented a chance to go see for myself. The place is beautiful, perhaps not inside the prison itself, but Fort Leavenworth as a whole is quite attractive. The Santa Fe and Oregon trails crossed the Missouri River here at Ft. Leavenworth, and you can still see the depressions from the wagon trains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Martin Alabama</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-alabama-lk-martin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-alabama-lk-martin/</guid>
      <description>Mom is a small town girl from Dadeville, Alabama. Small towns often have big families, and her Pearson family is no exception. There were three girls and three boys in her family, so I had five sets of aunts and uncles - all of whom resided in Alabama or returned to the state for their retirement. Pearson family reunions are held every summer at an uncle&amp;rsquo;s lake house, and we try to make it each year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camping in Florida</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-florida-camping/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-florida-camping/</guid>
      <description>Camping in several of Florida&amp;rsquo;s State Parks has been very enjoyable trips creating fond memories. In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll list them by region within the state.
Big Lagoon State Park, Pensacola - camp siteSouth Florida The Florida Keys I&amp;rsquo;ve been camping in the Florida Keys twice. Both were very short, one night visits. The first was in a private campground down close to Key West. I don&amp;rsquo;t recall the name or specific location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Southwest Florida</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-florida-sarasota/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-florida-sarasota/</guid>
      <description>Beautiful Sarasota was our home during the 2000&amp;rsquo;s, arriving for a new job just months after getting married in 1999. This Gulf coast town and its brilliant white sand beaches is where we started our family with a puppy, and then two sons. This post describes many of my favorite places and activities in southwest Florida - the places I miss the most.
Homes But I&amp;rsquo;ll start with where we lived.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baton Rouge Sights</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-louisiana-baton-rouge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-louisiana-baton-rouge/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve had friends and family come to visit over the years and we&amp;rsquo;re always looking for things to do and places to show them. So, I built a list! Most of these attractions involve history and culture that are unique to Baton Rouge. Below you&amp;rsquo;ll find a collection of my remarks, photos, and a map or two. Back Story As Edwin Edwards remarked about his governorships, I consider myself to be an &amp;ldquo;occasional&amp;rdquo; resident of Baton Rouge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camping in Louisiana</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-louisiana-camping/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-louisiana-camping/</guid>
      <description>My sons and I have enjoyed several tent camping trips in Louisiana and southern Mississippi. Sometimes, their friends have gone with us, and one trip was a church youth trip (which you&amp;rsquo;ll agree, aren&amp;rsquo;t typical camping trips.)
North Louisiana Caney Lake Campground - above Minden was a fun trip with our cousins. We all shared a campsite and everyone managed to find a space to spread out their sleeping bag in one of two tents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camping in South Mississippi</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-mississippi-camping/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-mississippi-camping/</guid>
      <description>Mississippi offers several beautiful campgrounds within an easy drive of Baton Rouge.
South Mississippi All of my tent camping experience in Mississippi has been in the southern part of the state. It&amp;rsquo;s a reasonably short drive from my home in Baton Rouge.
Clear Springs in Homochitto Forest Clear Springs campground is a hidden gem. Forest camping is terrific here surrounding this beautiful reservoir and facilities constructed during the Works Progress Administration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Orleans Sights</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-louisiana-new-orleans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-louisiana-new-orleans/</guid>
      <description>As Baton Rouge is just an hour&amp;rsquo;s drive from the Big Easy, we get down for visits with friends and sightseeing several times each year.
History Below I offer my big, bad overview of the history of New Orleans; based on a variety of sources from the web or print books I&amp;rsquo;ve read over the years. I&amp;rsquo;ve failed to properly document them, so if this were a middle school English paper I&amp;rsquo;d get an &amp;ldquo;F&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Washington DC Trip</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-dc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-dc/</guid>
      <description>My family was fortunate to be able to visit our nation&amp;rsquo;s capital right at the peak of the cherry blossoms during spring break of 2016. My oldest brother Fred and his wife Bonnie generously opened their home to us, inviting us to stay and also going with us on several days to visit the National Mall, enjoy some great dining, and ride the MetroRail around D.C. They live south of the city near one of the rail stops which makes commuting in very convenient.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
