<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>web design on HowIsJT</title>
    <link>https://howisjt.com/tags/web-design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in web design on HowIsJT</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 19:00:52 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://howisjt.com/tags/web-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Shortcodes Test</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/tech-shortcodes-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/tech-shortcodes-test/</guid>
      <description>Hugo Shortcodes Shortcodes are little snippets of code that can be called from within a post to perform an action. Hugo comes with a few shortcodes baked in such as &amp;ldquo;figure&amp;rdquo;, but others I&amp;rsquo;ve gleaned from internet searches and perhaps from my own tinkering.
Folder-based Image Gallery from a folder of pictures within &amp;ldquo;website/hugo/howisjt/static/&amp;rdquo;. Don&amp;rsquo;t put a slash in front of the &amp;ldquo;images&amp;rdquo; directory. This is different from all others. Youtube Just insert &amp;ldquo;youtube&amp;rdquo; with the unique video code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Image Gallery</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/tech-hugo-image-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/tech-hugo-image-gallery/</guid>
      <description>My new Hugo blog website wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be complete without the ability to host and display photos in an efficient, quick loading and mobile friendly manner. I searched around a bit examining several options. Each has pros and cons in my opinion, yet none of the sources for this code seemed to acknowledge the existence of the others. I&amp;rsquo;m providing links to the source where I found each of these, although those developers may have pulled it from somewhere else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Development Projects</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/tech-web-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/tech-web-development/</guid>
      <description>My earliest website development began with static sites hosted at GeoCities and other no-cost hosting providers. Each never amounted to more than a dozen or so pages each, but I learned the basics of HTML and CSS. Future employment led me to WordPress and then to Drupal frameworks. Each presented benefits, challenges, and learning opportunities.
Twitter Bootstrap Site content development with WordPress - specifically custom coding certain pages to achieve desired effects - led me back to hard-coding.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
