<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Louisiana on HowIsJT</title>
    <link>https://howisjt.com/tags/louisiana/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Louisiana on HowIsJT</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://howisjt.com/tags/louisiana/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Paddling Bayou Barbary</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-paddling-barbary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-paddling-barbary/</guid>
      <description>Pete&amp;rsquo;s Landing is a boat ramp ($5 launch fee) into scenic Bayou Barbary, a tributary of the Amite River located in Livingston Parish south of I-12. Pete&amp;rsquo;s is on hwy. 444, about midway between French Settlement and Killian, a little east of Hwy. 63. From the launch Barbary extends approximately 2 miles to the Amite.
First Visit I&amp;rsquo;d read of other&amp;rsquo;s paddling trips on Bayou Barbary and recommendations from friends who fished the bayou from their powered boats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayou Manchac</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-paddling-manchac/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-paddling-manchac/</guid>
      <description>My residence in southeast East Baton Rouge parish is less than 1-1/5 miles from the Amite River and 4-1/2 miles as the crow flies from Bayou Manchac. Having an enjoyment of paddling I&amp;rsquo;ve been on several excursions on the lower Manchac out to the Amite and back. I discovered a boat ramp into Bayou Manchac at the end of Ducros Rd, off Hwy. 42 in Prairieville. I&amp;rsquo;ve not paddled down the Amite itself - too chicken - as I&amp;rsquo;ve read of the hazards of current, fallen trees and snags.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shreveport Points of Interest</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-louisiana-shreveport/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-louisiana-shreveport/</guid>
      <description>Shreveport is my wife&amp;rsquo;s hometown so we get there fairly regularly. Here are a few places I like to visit.
Eats While there&amp;rsquo;s more to do in Shreveport than eat, let&amp;rsquo;s just say that there is no reason to go hungry while you&amp;rsquo;re there&amp;hellip;
Herby K&amp;rsquo;s Home of the shrimp buster sandwich.
They take about three jumbo shrimp and butterfly them, lightly deep fry them, and drop them on a poboy bun with lettuce and tomato.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avery Island</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-avery-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-avery-island/</guid>
      <description>During a day-trip to Avery Island we learned there&amp;rsquo;s much more to this south Louisiana curiosity than just hot sauce. There are two paid attractions on Avery Island: 1) Tours of the Tabasco factory (self-guided ~$5.50 each, more for guided group tours) and 2) Driving tour of the Jungle Gardens (additional $7 per person). Fees are for adults. There are slight discounts for seniors and young children.
Jeep photo opp for our kids We enjoyed our visit on the Friday following July 4, 2019, but we didn&amp;rsquo;t realize the plant would be closed for the holiday weekend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baton Rouge Sights</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-louisiana-baton-rouge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-louisiana-baton-rouge/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve had friends and family come to visit over the years and we&amp;rsquo;re always looking for things to do and places to show them. So, I built a list! Most of these attractions involve history and culture that are unique to Baton Rouge. Below you&amp;rsquo;ll find a collection of my remarks, photos, and a map or two. Back Story As Edwin Edwards remarked about his governorships, I consider myself to be an &amp;ldquo;occasional&amp;rdquo; resident of Baton Rouge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camping in Louisiana</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-louisiana-camping/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-louisiana-camping/</guid>
      <description>My sons and I have enjoyed several tent camping trips in Louisiana and southern Mississippi. Sometimes, their friends have gone with us, and one trip was a church youth trip (which you&amp;rsquo;ll agree, aren&amp;rsquo;t typical camping trips.)
North Louisiana Caney Lake Campground - above Minden was a fun trip with our cousins. We all shared a campsite and everyone managed to find a space to spread out their sleeping bag in one of two tents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Orleans Sights</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-louisiana-new-orleans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-louisiana-new-orleans/</guid>
      <description>As Baton Rouge is just an hour&amp;rsquo;s drive from the Big Easy, we get down for visits with friends and sightseeing several times each year.
History Below I offer my big, bad overview of the history of New Orleans; based on a variety of sources from the web or print books I&amp;rsquo;ve read over the years. I&amp;rsquo;ve failed to properly document them, so if this were a middle school English paper I&amp;rsquo;d get an &amp;ldquo;F&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
