<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hobbies on HowIsJT</title>
    <link>https://howisjt.com/categories/hobbies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hobbies on HowIsJT</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 19:00:52 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://howisjt.com/categories/hobbies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kayak Build</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-paddling-kayak-build/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-paddling-kayak-build/</guid>
      <description>Finished! Well it took far longer than I anticipated &amp;ndash; nearly two years of weekends and holidays &amp;ndash; but I&amp;rsquo;ve completed this project. I&amp;rsquo;ve documented the process in a stand-alone blog linked below. It was written diary style rather than &amp;ldquo;instructables&amp;rdquo; style, but contains numerous images, galleries, lessons learned and even a few videos. It would be helpful to anyone considering taking on a stitch-and-glue boat project such as this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Florida&#39;s Santa Fe River</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-florida-santafe-river/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 01:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-florida-santafe-river/</guid>
      <description>Officially, Florida&amp;rsquo;s Santa Fe originates from Santa Fe Lake, northeast of Gainesville, and flows 75 miles westward until it meets the Suwanee. For three miles, the river actually dives underground forming the famous natural bridge over which Florida&amp;rsquo;s old Bellamy Road crossed. The &amp;ldquo;sink&amp;rdquo; is in scenic O&amp;rsquo;Leno (Old Leno) State Park and the &amp;ldquo;rise&amp;rdquo; three miles downstream is in River Rise State Park off US 41/441. This behavior is not uncommon of streams in karst limestone regions and it neatly divides the Santa Fe into up-river and down-river.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birding in the South</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-birding/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-birding/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been interested in and fascinated by birds since childhood. During my high school and college years I forgot about it, not picking it back up again until I began my professional career.
Rekindled Interest My coworker Scott Knaus corrected my mis-identification of a chickadee, which I had foolishly called a &amp;ldquo;Black Capped&amp;rdquo; and he informed me it was more likely a &amp;ldquo;Carolina&amp;rdquo;. Oh, right. Many would have left it right there, but as my education included plant science and I appreciated the concept of &amp;ldquo;species,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;variety&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;cultivar,&amp;rdquo; I understood Scott&amp;rsquo;s point immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camping Chuck Box</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-camping-chuckbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-camping-chuckbox/</guid>
      <description>The kitchen and food prep is always a challenge when tent camping with the family. As a kid my dad took us camping in western North Carolina and I (vaguely) recall a rather elaborate setup with two large tents facing each other, and a heavy canvas tarp stretched in between, covering and protecting our dining and cooking area. There were boxes of food and supplies, large ice coolers, a Coleman stove and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classic Celestron C8</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-astronomy-celestron/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 01:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-astronomy-celestron/</guid>
      <description>Back Story As a kid during the 1970&amp;rsquo;s I had two older brothers, both science whizzes, who got into amateur astronomy during their high school years. Guided by a fairly remarkable high school science teacher, one brother nearly won the state science fair through his experimentation with chilled film in a fabricated camera body conducting astrophotography. I was too young to really understand what he was doing, but my father bought the latest, greatest Schmidt-Cassgrain telescope for his sons to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paddling</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-paddling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-paddling/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed being on the water since childhood and have fond memories of family reunions at my cousin&amp;rsquo;s lake houses where we&amp;rsquo;d swim, boat, water ski, and play.
Kayaking Residing just a couple miles from the beach in Sarasota, Florida caused me to break a commandment. Yes, I coveted my neighbor&amp;rsquo;s kayak. Not my actual neighbor, as he didn&amp;rsquo;t have one, but essentially any kayak I saw riding the roof rack of so, so many cars down local roads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeking Dark Skies</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-astronomy-dark-sky/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-astronomy-dark-sky/</guid>
      <description>Until my interest in astronomy was resurrected in 2015 I never really gave city lights a second thought except when they shined through my bedroom window at night or when I considered the plight of sea turtles. As a Florida resident the problem with municipal and private property lighting along beaches was well known through the efforts of activists and subsequent legislation that seems to be making a positive difference for turtle hatchlings along at least some beaches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>America&#39;s Great Solar Eclipse of 2017</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-astronomy-eclipse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-astronomy-eclipse/</guid>
      <description>By stroke of good fortune, one of my brothers lives outside of Anderson, South Carolina. His home was nearly in the center of the solar eclipse path, so I traveled from Louisiana with our family telescope to observe the eclipse with he, his wife, sons and friends. We enjoyed nearly perfectly clear skies for most of the event, though others - even family residing just a dozen miles away - suffered overcast skies totally obscuring totality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repowering a Snapper Comet</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-snapper-repower/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-snapper-repower/</guid>
      <description>I inherited a 27&amp;quot; Snapper Comet riding mower from a neighbor after it&amp;rsquo;s engine blew. Turns out, the owner had failed to change and ensure adequate engine oil, so it seised. I happily accepted the donation, initially attempted to rebuild the Honda engine, but eventually replaced it with a new engine. It ran well for a few years. Here&amp;rsquo;s the story.
A Gift Snapper A neighbor living a block away was the original owner.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
