<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>astronomy on HowIsJT</title>
    <link>https://howisjt.com/tags/astronomy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in astronomy on HowIsJT</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 01:00:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://howisjt.com/tags/astronomy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Classic Celestron C8</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-astronomy-celestron/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 01:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-astronomy-celestron/</guid>
      <description>Back Story As a kid during the 1970&amp;rsquo;s I had two older brothers, both science whizzes, who got into amateur astronomy during their high school years. Guided by a fairly remarkable high school science teacher, one brother nearly won the state science fair through his experimentation with chilled film in a fabricated camera body conducting astrophotography. I was too young to really understand what he was doing, but my father bought the latest, greatest Schmidt-Cassgrain telescope for his sons to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeking Dark Skies</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-astronomy-dark-sky/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-astronomy-dark-sky/</guid>
      <description>Until my interest in astronomy was resurrected in 2015 I never really gave city lights a second thought except when they shined through my bedroom window at night or when I considered the plight of sea turtles. As a Florida resident the problem with municipal and private property lighting along beaches was well known through the efforts of activists and subsequent legislation that seems to be making a positive difference for turtle hatchlings along at least some beaches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>America&#39;s Great Solar Eclipse of 2017</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-astronomy-eclipse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/hobby-astronomy-eclipse/</guid>
      <description>By stroke of good fortune, one of my brothers lives outside of Anderson, South Carolina. His home was nearly in the center of the solar eclipse path, so I traveled from Louisiana with our family telescope to observe the eclipse with he, his wife, sons and friends. We enjoyed nearly perfectly clear skies for most of the event, though others - even family residing just a dozen miles away - suffered overcast skies totally obscuring totality.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
