<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>family on HowIsJT</title>
    <link>https://howisjt.com/tags/family/</link>
    <description>Recent content in family on HowIsJT</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://howisjt.com/tags/family/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chicago</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-chicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-chicago/</guid>
      <description>My wife, sons and I spent four fantastic days exploring downtown Chicago visiting museums, galleries, parks and restaurants. We anticipated a typical summer trip, but our arrival coincided with a late season cold front which brought several days of unseasonably cool weather following that initial day of rain.
Trip Planning CitiPass claims they save you 48%. I didn&amp;rsquo;t do the math, but that seems about right. Citipass saved us hundreds of dollars and provided perks at most of the museums including 3D movies, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yancey County, NC</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-burnsville/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-burnsville/</guid>
      <description>View my Google photo album of this trip. Also in the works is a video of our adventures and sight seeing.
I spent part of my youth growing up on a beautiful farm outside of Burnsville, NC. We were a hard working family on a beautiful 120+ acre property fronting the Cane River where we raised beef cattle and grew tobacco and feed corn, eventually transitioning to blueberries, raspberries and blackberries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avery Island</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-avery-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-avery-island/</guid>
      <description>During a day-trip to Avery Island we learned there&amp;rsquo;s much more to this south Louisiana curiosity than just hot sauce. There are two paid attractions on Avery Island: 1) Tours of the Tabasco factory (self-guided ~$5.50 each, more for guided group tours) and 2) Driving tour of the Jungle Gardens (additional $7 per person). Fees are for adults. There are slight discounts for seniors and young children.
Jeep photo opp for our kids We enjoyed our visit on the Friday following July 4, 2019, but we didn&amp;rsquo;t realize the plant would be closed for the holiday weekend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fort Leavenworth</title>
      <link>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-kansas-leavenworth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 19:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://howisjt.com/posts/travel-kansas-leavenworth/</guid>
      <description>The name Fort Leavenworth has always had ominous connotations to me. At the occasion of my oldest brother&amp;rsquo;s military retirement ceremony, I was presented a chance to go see for myself. The place is beautiful, perhaps not inside the prison itself, but Fort Leavenworth as a whole is quite attractive. The Santa Fe and Oregon trails crossed the Missouri River here at Ft. Leavenworth, and you can still see the depressions from the wagon trains.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
